Excuse me, sir. Sir, how did you get rich, man?
I grew channel to 21 million followers.
I've already been 47 billionaires in the States.
How did you get rich, man? What did you do?
I owned one of the
biggest f***ing companies in the world.
Are you serious?
What was the most amount of
money you made in a single year?
I sold the company in 2023 for 4.1 billion pounds.
So not dollars?
Proper money. 4.1 billion pounds.
About 5 billion.
A substantial nine-digit number.
900 million.
Double that?
You said double that?
Yeah.
Like 1.8 billion?
Of course.
That's a 10-digit number, my man.
10-digit.
That's a 10-digit number.
Did you ever have to pay a lot in taxes?
Oh, yeah.
A lot, yeah.
I paid nearly 100 million pounds in
tax, but it was worth it because...
So the taxes are crazy here.
Tax is crazy. If I will
sell my company, I will leave.
Is there a tax hack
that you have for business owners?
Number one expense is...
There are nine steps. Number one is...
I've interviewed more billionaires than
anybody else in the world,
and I've asked every single one of them,
how they got rich.
But today, I'm doing something different.
I'm asking them the one
question that nobody wants to ask.
Do you actually pay your taxes?
And there's no better place
to ask it than here, London.
One of the most taxed cities in the world.
A place filled with millionaires and billionaires.
So I'm going straight up to the richest
people in the city to ask them one
of the most controversial questions out there.
So let's see what they have to say.
All right, you guys.
We're headed right now to go
get our first interview out here.
But like I was saying earlier, man, guys,
the UK taxes are out of this world.
If you're making serious money out here,
you could be paying 45% in taxes.
Guys, that's half of all your money.
So I'm really curious to figure out what
the richest people out here think about that,
whether or not they actually pay their taxes.
Excuse me, sir. Sir, how did you become wealthy?
Sorry?
I said, how did you become wealthy?
He's saying life.
Life.
There you go. Absolutely. Thank you, guys.
Excuse me, sir.
I have a question for you.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
Thirty two. And how did you get rich?
What line of business were you in?
Real quick, sir. I've interviewed 47 billionaires.
Could I get one minute with you real quick?
Excuse me, ma'am.
Question for you. How old were
you when you became a millionaire?
Excuse me, sir. Sir, question for you.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
I can't talk to you. Real quick, sir.
I have a channel with 21 million followers.
I interview 16.
Could I get 30 seconds with you real quick?
What line of business were you in?
What line of business were you in, sir?
You what?
No, you didn't. Real quick, sir.
This is to help the younger generation.
I haven't gotten anybody today.
Could I get you for just 30 seconds?
Could I get your contact?
Wow.
Guys, look, we have been out here
for hours in London, but it's been nonstop
rejection after rejection, so we
have got to change things up.
And we are right now heading into what is
apparently the wealthiest part in all of London.
Mayfair, the billionaire's playground out
here where all the richest people
congregate to hopefully find some
millionaires and billionaires to stop and
give us the game for you guys.
Let's go see who we can find.
All right, guys, look, so
my guys point up right here.
This is like a three or four million dollar car.
You guys, we're going to get him coming
out to figure out how he got rich.
Come on. Excuse me, sir.
Sir, how did you get rich, man?
I grew to 21 million followers.
I've been even 47 billionaires in the States.
How did you get rich? What did you do?
If you think this is
rich, then you've got it mistaken.
What kind of business? I'm a jeweler.
You're a jeweler. How did you get into that business?
I grew up watching people hustling.
I watch people buy and sell
cars, went hand in hand with watches.
And I did watches.
For many, many years, I was probably one
of the biggest watch dealers at my time.
Ten years ago doing it.
Now I've just put all
my time and effort into cars.
Hyper cars. How much does that car cost?
Today's price? Four and a half million pounds.
You said four and a half million?
As a jeweler, how important is
it to keep your word in business?
Word is everything. Word is everything.
I deal with people who break their word.
They automatically pay compensation.
It's simple as that.
I won't deal with somebody the minute
that they have broken their word
and have done nothing to compensate.
Have you got to stand on business?
Have you ever been f***ed over in business?
Oh, plenty of times. Business, life, who hasn't?
You wouldn't get to where you want
to get to without going through it.
Did you come from a rich family growing up?
No. You didn't?
Nah. Most of my family are not rich.
I'm not class, consider myself rich.
But they don't drive the guardies.
But they're happy with what they
do and I'm happy for them.
What was your turning point to financial freedom?
What was that moment in
your life where you were like,
I want to go out there and build
a little bit of an empire for myself?
A turning point for me is when
I probably had my son and I thought,
I need to level up,
I need to set an example.
And now I've got a
daughter, I'll do it even more.
I want her to be accustomed to everything
I've got and not be fazed by it
when somebody tries to please her in it.
So I've got to plan and prepare for that.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
About $25 million.
$25 million.
That was during COVID.
Watches were $700,000, $800,000 each and I
was selling two, three watches a week.
Now, a lot of young people, they
think that when they start a business,
once they start to make money, they're going to
be able to go out and buy cars like that.
Was that the case for you in the beginning
or how long was it before it started to...
I've had a passion for cars
ever since I was a kid.
I always knew I was
going to have a nice car.
I worked my way to that car.
Do you think a lot of young people, they go out
and buy cars before they really should afford to do that?
Oh yeah, yeah, everyone does it.
Everyone does it. I've done it. We've all done it.
Do you regret it? Do you regret it?
No, I don't regret it.
You can't regret anything in life.
Everything is a lesson.
It makes you a better person the following year.
So when I see 20-year-old kids making
all this money off crypto, doing their thing,
a lot of hate on Instagram, whatever, you know,
they've got to learn the
hard way or the easy way.
It's a lesson. Good luck to them.
Did you have to ever pay a lot in taxes?
Oh yeah, all the time.
Do you have a tax hack for
anybody in business? Was there a tax hack?
No, no, no, there's no
hack. You can't hack tax me.
Really?
You try to hack tax, you're going
to jail. So it's not worth it.
Is there not like a tax
code or something that you can do?
Oh, there's always something, but
it's not a hack. There's expenses.
A lot of people don't realize
what their day-to-day life is an expense.
So you paid your taxes?
Yeah, of course.
Final question for you. What keeps
poor people poor in today's world?
When you look at society as a
whole, what keeps people broke in today's world?
The fact that they're broke is a choice.
Black homeless people, a choice. Not
everybody, but majority have a choice.
You're born with the same hands,
feet, legs, eyes as everybody else.
So why?
Are you choosing to be broke?
Just get a job.
Broke is if you overspend your money
or you f***ed up some way in life.
Sorry.
For me, I don't see being poor as an option.
I don't know anybody who's poor.
People I know have less money,
but I don't know anybody who's poor.
Thank you, my friend. You got great advice.
Thank you for your time, my friend.
Have a great day, my man. Thank you.
Guys, look, I just went up
to my guy coming out of that,
like four and a half million dollar car.
I'm pretty sure, like he said,
he said, I know you, man.
Look, he's tapped in, man.
He sees all the billionaires that we're interviewing.
He just dropped some straight game right there.
And I love at the end of that interview
when he said, look, being poor is a choice, guys.
We were all given abilities to go
out there, create wealth, create abundance for ourselves,
whether it's in the form of
getting a job or starting a business.
Great interview out there.
I'm taking notes on that with myself.
We got to keep this thing rolling
and go get this next interview, you guys.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir, how did you get rich?
How did I get rich?
Have you ever had to call a plumber?
A plumber?
I owned one of the
biggest plumbing companies in the world.
Are you serious?
How big was the company?
What was the most amount of
money you made a single year?
I sold the company in 2023.
For
4.1 billion pounds.
So not dollars?
Top of money.
4.1 billion pounds.
Can I interview you for a minute?
I go all over the world
interviewing billionaires to help the younger generation.
I'm in a hurry, but...
Just for one minute.
I can give you five minutes.
Is that okay?
Absolutely.
Did you come from a lot of money growing up?
No, I didn't.
My dad was in the civil service.
My great grandparents were mill
owners in Huddersfield and West Yorkshire.
They lost all the money
in the Great Depression of 1929.
So he said, don't go into business.
But I was inspired by Lord Hanson, famous industrialist.
From the 1960s.
I remember to this day, my dad lifted me
on his shoulders and we looked over the wall
of the big house at the end of
the cul-de-sac in Yorkshire and watched the helicopter land.
I remember saying, dad, I want one of those.
He said, well, don't be in the
civil service like me earning a pittance.
You need to run your own business.
That's the day I wanted to be an entrepreneur.
Even if I didn't know that word.
This is fascinating to me because
we're talking about plumbing, home services here.
This isn't a necessarily sexy business, but you
built it into a 4 billion pound company.
Talk to that young person out there that
thinks that they have to go invent the next
Google.
There's a lot of opportunities in
some of these really niche, unsexy businesses.
Yeah, you don't.
My advice to any aspiring entrepreneur would
be, first of all, copy a business model.
We're taught at school that copying homework is bad.
In business, I would say copy and then improve slightly.
So don't reinvent the wheel.
Don't reinvent the wheel.
Go and buy a copy of Entrepreneur Magazine.
It's got all of the franchise businesses listed.
Run through it.
Decide which is the business you want to run.
Copy their model, but do it yourself.
Don't buy a franchise.
Hire a few people.
Get people to work for you.
And that's how you become very wealthy.
I'm going to challenge you, Richard.
Take me back to the
most life-changing conversation you ever had.
What is the greatest piece of
advice that you've received throughout your career?
It was from Jim Collins, who wrote the
book Good to Great, the second best business book
ever written.
And he said, to be successful,
you need to be a hedgehog.
Entrepreneurs are like me.
We're all foxes.
We're always looking for the next opportunity.
We have an idea every day, and we
need to be hedgehogs moving in a methodical direction.
If somebody comes along and has a harebrained
idea, we put up our prickles, we ignore it,
and we keep going with a
very simple, clear model without distractions.
So you said that that was the
second best business book that's ever been written.
What's the first one?
The best book that's ever been written is
called How to Make a Billion in Nine Steps.
Who's that by?
It became a bestseller in the Sunday Times
list when it came out in July last year,
and it's written by me, Richard Harpin.
So how does someone make a billion dollars?
Tell me right now, man.
How does somebody make a billion dollars?
There are nine steps.
Number one is copy.
And pivot.
Second one, get an investor
to help your business to scale.
Thirdly, get a coach and a mentor.
Really important to learn from others.
Number four, have an omnichannel model.
You don't just want to be online.
You need to have stores or pop-up stands.
You can't just rely upon the internet these days.
Number five, the hardest step
for any entrepreneur, hire your replacement.
Hire somebody that's better than
you to run the day-to-day business.
Hire a hedgehog because as entrepreneurs,
we're foxes with too many ideas.
Step six, go global with locals.
You can't send a Brit to America.
You can't send an American to Britain.
You've got to hire a
local to head up your business.
Otherwise, you won't be taken seriously.
Step number seven is evolution, not revolution.
There is a role for revolution
right at the start of a business,
but thereafter, keep evolving your business.
We know lots of businesses that didn't keep evolving.
Blockbuster, Nokia, Yellow Pages.
They're dead or a shadow of their former selves.
Number eight, how many people,
if we ask them around here,
have you got a to-do list?
Everybody would put up the hand.
Have you got a to-do list?
Everybody puts up the hand.
If you say, have you got a not to-do list?
Nobody puts up the hand.
I do now because I've learned that a not
to-do list is more important than a to-do list.
And the final step to make
a billion pounds is hone your character.
This is about forget the stuff that you're bad at.
And I was bad at loads of stuff.
And focus on the things that you're really good at
and hire other people.
And I want people to do those
other things that we don't like doing,
like running the day to
day, get them to do it.
So you can focus on the vision
and the growth and the business development.
Richard, you know they don't teach this in school, right?
I wish they did.
What is the most amount of money
you paid in taxes in one year?
I paid nearly 100 million pounds
in tax when I sold HomeServe,
but it was worth it because
I made a lot of money.
And I do believe in giving back and paying taxes.
I don't believe in running off
and living in a tax-free environment.
So you think that billionaires should pay their taxes?
Absolutely.
So long as they stay relatively low and affordable,
then here is a great place
from which to start a business,
scale a business and turn it global.
How old are you now?
61 years old.
If me and you died tomorrow
and you had one more message
to leave with the younger generation, what would that be?
I would say if you're thinking
about setting up a business today,
what's your skill?
What do you enjoy doing?
Is it sales and marketing?
Is it finance?
Is it operations?
Then go and work for a big company,
in an industry that you like and
get experience for two or three years.
Then go and work for a
smaller entrepreneurial company in that same role,
whether that's sales or marketing, finance or operations.
After you've got five or six years of experience,
go and negotiate with somebody else
that might be retiring and say,
I'll buy your business, but I'll pay you over
three or four years out of the future profits.
So you can buy a business, it's
lower risk than setting up from scratch,
and you can use their money to
acquire it, which is called vendor finance.
That's beautiful advice, Frank.
Thank you so much for your time.
Thank you.
I connect with all the billionaires I interview.
Could I get your contact?
Yeah, of course.
Guys, I just finished interviewing someone who built
and sold a company for over 4.1 billion pounds.
And I want you to really
think about this for a second.
You're sitting here right now watching these interviews,
but what if you could actually talk to these people?
What if you could ask them your questions
about your business, your life, and your next move,
and get an answer directly from someone who's
already built a company worth hundreds of millions
and billions of dollars?
That's exactly why I'm doing something insane on April 22nd,
in less than two weeks.
I'm going to be hosting one of
the craziest events of the entire year.
I'm hosting three live Zoom
calls with entrepreneurs who have built
and sold companies at the highest level.
Now, who are these people?
First, we're going to have on Clint Phillips,
who sold his healthcare company for $460 million.
Then, Steven Ellsworth, the founder of Poppy.
He grew this company from zero to $500 million in
less than five years and sold it to Pepsi for $2
billion.
And finally, Edward Ewing, a private
equity billionaire who buys and scales companies,
and he's a big fan of the company.
And he's also the founder of the company,
which is a company that's
been running for a long time,
and he's been talking to companies for a living.
And here's the thing, guys.
This is not a podcast.
This is not some replay.
You are on the call live.
You'll be able to ask your questions and
get real answers from people who have actually
done it.
These are the kinds of conversations that
can completely change your business and your
life.
Now, here's the craziest part, guys.
If you join right now by going down and
clicking the link in the description in this video,
you can get access to this once in a
lifetime event on April 22nd for free, and become a
member of the number one entrepreneur
community, and network, in the entire world.
So, if you want to get access to the
three live Zoom calls on April 22nd, all you have
to do is go down, click the link in the
description of this video, you grab your spot now, and
I'll see you there.
With that being said, let's go get this next interview.
Excuse me, sir.
How old were you when you became a millionaire?
Sorry?
Good question.
What?
Long time ago.
Long time ago?
And how did you get rich that early?
What line of business were you in?
Retail of mobile phones.
Where are you from?
Russia.
You're from Russia?
Yeah.
So, how long have you been a business owner?
From 22.
Since 22 years old?
Yeah.
Let me ask you a question.
Did you come from a lot of money?
Did you grow up with a lot of money?
No, no.
I grew up in a social house.
So, what was your turning point to financial freedom?
The Soviet Union crashed when I was 17 years old.
It was a huge opportunity to
grow up, to make money, to trade.
Because, you know, I was a businessman.
Because a lot of people, Soviet people,
they have no clue how to trade.
At that time, when oil prices and
everything started growing up and mobile phones became
very popular, we just catch the wave.
What was the most amount of
money that you made this year?
Total revenue in 2008 was about 5 billion.
You said 5 billion dollars?
Yeah.
So, do you live in London now?
Yeah, for 18 years.
Is this a good city to become an entrepreneur?
I live in the States, so I'm
trying to learn about the business in London.
Now, not.
Now, everybody's gone.
Everybody's going, living because of the taxes.
We have a socialist in the government.
It's like you're mayor of New York.
The same group of gangsters that take
other people's money for eating rich and spreading
through the poor.
Did you have to pay
a lot of money in taxes?
Of course, yes.
So, the taxes are crazy here.
Tax is crazy.
If I will sell my company, I will leave.
I will leave the UK.
Business owners, they made their first
million not a long time ago.
Yeah, that's right.
It's 50.
51 years old today.
This year, 52.
If me and you died tomorrow and you had
one more message to leave with the younger generation,
what would that be?
Read the books.
Did you read a lot of books?
Not enough.
That's why I left the Forbes list.
You were on the Forbes list at one point?
Yeah, when I was young.
So, you were a billionaire?
Young Forbes, before 30.
Wow.
Are you a billionaire?
No, no, no.
You were though, at one point.
You was.
Let me ask you this.
What was the number one book that changed your life?
Number one books?
Yes.
What was number one?
Your number one book recommendation for anybody in business?
Ayn Rand, Atlas Shrugged.
What's that about?
Capitalism.
So, how does money work?
For the people that don't know
it, give them a quick masterclass.
Somebody wants to get rich in today's world.
Give them these last 20 seconds right here.
How does somebody become
a multi-millionaire in today's world?
You have to be in the right place.
Look at the cars around.
Why are you here?
Ferrari, Ferrari, McLaren.
First of all, location when already rich people here.
So, proximity is power.
Yeah.
Second one, assortment.
It has to be popular and great.
And very important to motivate your team to work.
This is my place.
This is Lucas' business.
You own this restaurant right here?
Yes.
Thank you for your time, sir.
You're welcome.
I appreciate that.
Have a great day, my friend.
Thank you for stopping me, man.
I appreciate it.
Hey, look at that fit, you guys, man.
That's the $5 billion man right there, man.
He just dropped some great advice.
When I was like, man, saw him across
the street, he had that fit going crazy.
So, we had to stop him.
He just gave some solid bombs.
But I love what he said, man.
He said, look at the street.
You got Ferrari, Ferrari, Ferrari,
Rolls Royce, Bentley all over.
Proximity is power.
The faster you can follow the money,
the quicker you're going to get to it.
Great interview out here in London.
We got to keep this thing rolling
and go get this next interview, guys.
Come on.
Sir, question for you.
How old were you when you became a billionaire?
Yes, sir.
How did you get rich?
Well, I've been very fortunate as part
of a family business to start with.
But obviously, you know, still ambitious
enough to build up on that.
What type of company?
Originally, we come out of
the offshore energy marine services business.
And you own that business today?
We sold that business and we've set
up the second iteration of that business,
which is now collaborating with the franchise.
How much?
$5 billion.
What did you all sell that company for?
A north of a substantial nine digit number.
More than $100 million?
Yeah.
More than $200 million?
Significantly more than that.
$900 million?
Double that.
You said double that?
Yeah.
Like $1.8 billion?
那是十字数
Did you kind of own
the company when you sold it?
Yes, we did.
Full ownership of the business.
Was it you and partners?
Just father and I.
Father and you.
Yeah.
What's the number one piece of advice that
you got from your dad that helped you become
a successful entrepreneur?
What did he teach you about business?
Cost.
Cost management is key to everything, right?
So you got to keep your expenses low.
It's not about how much you sell it for.
It's about how much you're willing to buy
the product and be able to, you know, your
underlying cost, right?
If you can manage your cost, you
can manage to sell it in any condition.
I don't talk about this in business.
Yeah, 100%.
This is great advice.
It doesn't matter if you
can sell a product at $10.
If you're buying it for $8, you're
only making that margin at $2, right?
But if you can buy it at $2, you can sell
it at $5, you can sell it at $7, you can sell
it at $10.
This applies to any business.
Anything.
Literally anything in life.
A lot of people think that you
shouldn't do business with friends and family.
How do you feel about that?
I'll admit, working with family is extremely difficult.
For sure.
Right?
Did it almost sever the
relationship at any point in time?
For sure, right?
When you're going through trials and tribulations, it
was hard for him to step away from the
idea of being my father and actually see
me as, you know, an employee or a partner.
And the same for me.
It was hard for me to appreciate.
It took a while for me to appreciate and
understand that, you know, when he was getting tough on
us and tough on me, it wasn't coming
from a place that's personal, but rather because
there's an ambition for a greater
purpose here, which was the company.
Where are you a resident of?
I'm a resident of the UAE.
Of the UAE.
Yeah.
So when you had that big exit, you
didn't have to pay UK taxes, I'm assuming.
No, no.
We were very fortunate enough
not to be able to pay.
Did you have to pay a lot
in taxes when you had that exit?
Without divulging too much, no.
The way that the leadership there had been
able to build a country that sustains and
allows, you know, free movement.
Market and entrepreneurship.
We didn't have to pay the taxes.
Of course, there are other ways where you
have to pay back to your community, but I
think that's a personal choice of ours that
we do, whether it's in the UAE or outside.
So your advice to somebody that's trying not to
pay a ton in taxes is move to the UAE.
I mean, look, I'm pro-UAE all my life.
I was born there.
I was raised there.
We have full trust and belief in the
leadership and the direction that they're going in.
So I'll always be waving that flag.
Thank you so much for your time.
Appreciate it, man.
I can't believe I got interviewed by you.
Yes, sir.
Now you gave some great advice, man.
Nice to meet you, my man.
I follow you on TikTok.
I appreciate that.
Your interviewing skills are pretty amazing.
Thank you, brother.
I appreciate that.
Guys, that's a wrap on today's video.
I need you guys to stop right now.
Like, subscribe for amazing content coming every
week to the School of Hard Knocks.
But let's go even further.
Look, every single week, I host live Zoom
calls with the 8, 9, and 10-figure entrepreneurs
that I interview on this channel, where you
can ask your direct questions to them and
get mentored every week by the
millionaires and billionaires that I interview.
And you can get access right now if you
go down to the link in the description of this
video and join the number one most
powerful entrepreneur community and network in the
entire world.
It's called the School of Mentors.
I can't wait to see you on the inside.
That being said, we'll see you in the next video.